<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Varsha Bhat</title>
    <link>http://vnb.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Varsha Bhat</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 20:33:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://vnb.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Support Vector Machine</title>
      <link>http://vnb.github.io/posts/support-vector-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 20:33:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vnb.github.io/posts/support-vector-machine/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to SVM Support Vector Machines are the most commonly used supervised learning algorithms for classification problems. This post discusses the mathematics/intuition behind Linear SVM algorithms with a light introduction to Lagrange multipliers which is used for the optimization part.
Linear SVM: In a 2-D space there are 2 sets of points represented by their coordinates (x1, x2) and their labels represented by y with values 1 or -1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fraud Detection</title>
      <link>http://vnb.github.io/posts/fraud-detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://vnb.github.io/posts/fraud-detection/</guid>
      <description>Fraud detection
Most transactions on the internet take place through the use of credit/debit cards in order to complete a purchase. While most transactions are legitimately initiated by a customer, a small fraction of these transactions are fraudulent. Fraudulent transactions amount to 0.1% of all transactions but the losses from such activities could run upto billions of dollars per year. Therefore, it is important for e-commerce sites and banks likewise to be able to identify fraudulent behavior in a timely manner and in order to do this we can employ machine learning methods.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>